<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: netflix | Soul's website]]></title>
  <link href="http://sf3soft.net/blog/categories/netflix/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sf3soft.net/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-09T00:56:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sf3soft.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Soul]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TV Show Tracking]]></title>
    <link href="http://sf3soft.net/blog/2016/01/11/tv-tracking/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-11T16:29:57-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sf3soft.net/blog/2016/01/11/tv-tracking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So having just finished Person of Interest season 4, I thought it would be a good idea to update my SideReel account. SideReel is a nice site that I&rsquo;ve neglected use of for quite some time, even though I&rsquo;ve had an account for a little over 4 years now. I&rsquo;m just learning today how unfortunate that is. As I went to transfer my tracking progress from Netflix via my list, very quickly I found out that shows I was previously watching were no longer available to stream, and were removed completely from my list.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The most notable show I can think of that this affected for me would be 24, because I know I was fairly far into it when I stopped watching it. Now it&rsquo;s not on Netflix, so finding where I stopped will be a bit of a challenge.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I don&rsquo;t even know what shows <em>were</em> on the list, because Netflix silently removes them. Almost as bad as YouTube deleting videos. YouTube at least keeps the record there, so you can see that <em>something</em> was deleted. They aren&rsquo;t helping anyone though, because YouTube doesn&rsquo;t tell you <em>what</em> was deleted, only that it&rsquo;s gone now. They don&rsquo;t even save the title of the video, so you have no idea what it was. RIP playlists from 3 years ago.</p>

<p>I guess now I should try to remember to keep my tracking up-to-date, lest I lose more progress without even knowing it&rsquo;s gone&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
